## **Douglas Pleger**

# Full-Stack Developer | Renton, WA 707.803.3646 | <u>DougPleger@gmail.com</u> Portfolio.stamplayapp.com | Linkedin.com/in/douglaspleger

With an eye for elegant and clean design and a mind for effective and creative coding, as a web-developer I hope to bring something smart, accessible and useful to the online world. I'm passionate about keeping up on new technologies and I hope to land myself in a position where I can continue to challenge myself to grow and develop with our industry. I'll never turn down new opportunities to learn or help out my team and company!

As a former freelance artist and an amateur graphic designer, you'll find my layouts cohesive and easy to navigate while my logos are strong and memorable. With a very extensive customer-service and tech-support background, I'm great at communicating between people of various technical expertise! With the highest rated positive feedback in Nintendo's tech-support team and well over 8,000 calls under my belt between my various positions; it's become very important to me to ensure I always leave a position impression with those I work with. At Coding Dojo I learned the ins-and-outs of full front-to-back-end stacks in JavaScript, Python and Ruby and I'm always more than eager to jump into new technologies at a moment's notice. Whether it's Google Maps or SoundCloud API, tackling a new .js library or learning new tricks in SASS – I strive to never stop learning and expanding my technical toolkit!

In hiring me, you'll find someone who's strong unwavering focus will never falter in the face of long-hours, heavy workloads or a constantly changing environment. In hiring me, you'll find someone who isn't afraid of criticism and strives to provide nothing but the best for his team. In hiring me, you will find a loyal employee who will bare the company's name with pride.

Thank you for taking the time to read this and thank you for your consideration!

Sincerely,

Douglas Pleger

<u>DougPleger@gmail.com</u>
(707)803.3646

## **Douglas Pleger**

# Full-Stack Developer | Renton, WA 707.803.3646 | <u>DougPleger@gmail.com</u> Portfolio.stamplayapp.com | <u>Linkedin.com/in/douglaspleger</u>

#### **About Me**

Full-stack developer with a strong, passionate creative side. Highly focused, strong-willed and will never turn down an opportunity to help my team and company. Years of experience in communicating and working with others in fast-paced environments. Hoping to continue honing and expanding my programming experience as the industry grows and changes.

#### **Technical Tookit**

Front-End: HTML/CSS, jQuery, HTTP Request/Response, AJAX

Languages: JavaScript, Python, Ruby

Frameworks: Django, Rails, Express.js, Socket.io, Bootstrap, AngularJS

Version Control: Git, GitHub, Cloud9, STAMPlay

Databases: SQL(MySQL, Sqlite, PostgresSQL), NoSQL(MongoDB), Mongoose.js, ActiveRecords

Adobe Suite: Flash, PhotoShop, Illustrator, Acrobat

### Education

#### <u>Coding Dojo – Bellevue, WA</u>

Completed an intensive web development program covering multiple languages; spanning more than 1000 hours of active programming. Learned RESTful practices and worked closely with fellow students to create complex, real-world applications.

#### **Self-Directed Education**

Udacity(Coder's Manual), CodeCademy, W3Schools, StackSocial, Mozilla Developer Network

### **Employment History**

#### Pro Sports Club, Facility Operations | Bellevue, WA | October 2014 – October 2015

Worked overnight with a small team to provide routine maintenance to keep our fitness institution in top pristine quality. Focus on detail, efficiency and communication was needed to ensure us meeting the pedigree of the Pro Club name.

#### Zones Inc, Customer Service/Credit Entry | Auburn, WA | March 2012 – September 2014

Provided multiple-administrative roles: tracking and crediting returns, handling and correcting clerical errors and working with our shipping providers to track lost and missing shipments. Communicated between our sales force, warehouses and clients to ensure strong, seamless exchanges. Helped integrate new Microsoft Dynamics (AX) platform and created training materials necessary to train new overseas employees.

Nintendo of America, Tier-2 Wireless Tech Support | Redmond, WA | October 2010 – February 2012 Provided over-the-phone technical support to customers wishing to connect their Nintendo products online. Used concise communication skills to help anyone from younger children and elderly alike to identify wireless router products, make any necessary security or connectivity changes and ensure customer satisfaction. Provided detailed data-surveys upon each call. Recorded calls were used as positive examples in training classes.